Nerushan Naguleswaran

111 - 80 Orenda Crt, Brampton, ON, Canada, L6W3M9

□ (647) 525-4544 | ■ nerushan.n@hotmail.com | □ Neru9898 | □ Nerushan Naguleswaran

About

A self taught Software Engineer transitioning from Electrical Engineer who is willing to learn and improve on soft and technical skills. Experiences in agile teams, creating modern UI with modern languages and problem solving any issues appearing in the project life

Experience_

Software Engineer(Full Stack)

North York, Canada

GOJITECH

October 2021 - Present

- · Working in a fast growing Health-Tech startup company with a team software engineers aiming to modernize electronic health record(EHR/EMR) software
- Front-End Stack: React, Typescript, Ionic
- Back-End Stack: Node js, Typescript, TypeORM
- Using pre-existing EHR API and Postman to find issues or missing features to either improve or create API
- Using React, Ionic and SASS to create modular components and modern UI for the EMR
- Using Jira to manage personal task, report bugs or assign task

Sr. Technical Student

TORONTO HYDRO - METER DATA MANAGEMENT

January 2019 - Aug 2019

- · Managed and lead a team of 4 people on a major meter conversion project ensuring team cohesion and fulfilment of deadlines
- Conducted meter data maintenance in industry standard software, including ODS and MV90
- · Gathered meter information using PL/SQL from Oracle servers and used Excel macros to analyze and compare complex data sets
- · Organized and validated manufacturer data sheet specifications using SAP and communicated essential information with supervisor and senior technicians

Projects_

Team Lead

ENGINEERING CAPSTONE (ENG4000)

Sept 2020 - April 2021

- · Proposed by Toronto Hydro to explore the viability of Electrical Vehicle chargers and Battery Energy Storage System for Condos in
- Developed an extensive Python simulation for the Battery Energy System (Bess), Multi-Unit Residential Building (MURB), Ev chargers
- Using python developed the EV chargers and car flow simulations for both (real time and historical time)
- · Developed billing functionality for the MURB using Node.js and an energy management system platform to show the entire energy system in one environment
- · Organized meetings in order to communicate project progress with Toronto Hydro and created progress/other reports for course advisors

Skills_

Front-End Development HTML, CSS, SASS, Javascript, React, Bootstrap, Typescript, Ionic, Redux

Back-End Development Node.Js, Python

Database Development PL/SQL, MongoDB, Postgres

Project Management Tool Jira

Simulation and Numerical Tool MATLAB, Simulink, Spice, Psim

Other Languages and Tools Github, Bitbucket, Postman, C, C++, Java, Bash, Verilog, R-Studio, Unix/Linux Shell

Education

Bachelor of Engineering (BEng) in Electrical Engineering

LASSONDE SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING, YORK UNIVERSITY

June 2021